<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Recent Content on Olli Saarikivi </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://ulber.iki.fi/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 10:49:35 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reitit for Windows Phone 8.1</title>
      <link>http://ulber.iki.fi/2014/08/reitit-for-windows-phone-8.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 10:49:35 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ulber.iki.fi/2014/08/reitit-for-windows-phone-8.1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float: left; margin-right: 1em; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-top: 0.25em;&#34; src=&#34;/reitit.png&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the summer I have been developing a Windows Phone 8.1 version of my Helsinki metropolitan area route planner app, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.windowsphone.com/fi-fi/store/app/reitit/30e77f37-ef15-4860-b5d2-c4f7ee96f0e4&#34;&gt;Reitit&lt;/a&gt;. The new version is already mostly feature complete. However, the release of the app will be delayed due to problems I have encountered with the new framework:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app is too slow. Page navigation is noticeably slower than in the old version. One optimization that I employed in the WP7 version was to not use databinding and instead create and update all controls in code-behind. I hoped that this would not be required to get smooth navigation on WP8 class hardware. I will have to do further testing to see what is causing the slow page loading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/xaml/windows.ui.xaml.controls.maps.mapcontrol.aspx&#34;&gt;MapControl&lt;/a&gt; for &amp;ldquo;Windows Phone XAML apps&amp;rdquo; has rendering issues when panning a map that includes UIElement pushpins. Basically the pushpins don&amp;rsquo;t always move at the same speed as the rest of the map. When dragging a finger on the map, both the map image and the pushpins lag behind the touch point, but the map image itself lags &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; resulting in the pushpins not staying glued down on to the map.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue with the map control can be tolerated, as the map is otherwise quite a bit more beautiful than the old WP7 map. The page navigation issue, however, is something I will need to fix before publishing the new version.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://ulber.iki.fi/about</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 16:58:08 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ulber.iki.fi/about</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a doctoral student at &lt;a href=&#34;http://cse.aalto.fi/en/&#34; title=&#34;CSE&#34;&gt;Aalto University Department of Computer Science and Engineering&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Email&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:olli.saarikivi@iki.fi&#34;&gt;olli.saarikivi@iki.fi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Office Address&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aalto University School of Science&lt;br /&gt;
Department of Computer Science and Engineering&lt;br /&gt;
PO Box 15400, FI-00076 Aalto, Finland&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>http://ulber.iki.fi/cv</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 11:42:16 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ulber.iki.fi/cv</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Doctoral student&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sept. 2013 – present&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aalto University&lt;/em&gt;, Department Computer Science and Engineering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thesis working title is “Automated testing methods for concurrent
software”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;M.Sc. in Computer Science&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sept. 2011 – Aug. 2013&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aalto University&lt;/em&gt;, Department of Information and Computer Science&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thesis title was “Test-Guided Proofs for C Programs on LLVM”. My
instructors were Prof. Keijo Heljanko and Kari Kähkönen M.Sc. (Tech.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;B.Sc. in Computer Science&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sept. 2007 – Apr. 2011&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Helsinki University&lt;/em&gt;, Department of Computer Science&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Päivölä High School of Mathematics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;July 2004 – May 2006&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this I had the opportunity to work at Nokia Research Center,
thanks to a partnership between Nokia and the school. See the Work
Experience section for details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;K. Kähkönen, O. Saarikivi and K. Heljanko: &lt;em&gt;LCT: A Parallel Distributed
Testing Tool for Multithreaded Java Programs&lt;/em&gt;. In Proceedings of the
11th International Workshop on Parallel and Distributed Methods in
verifiCation (PDMC 2012), 17 September 2012, London, UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;K. Kähkönen, O. Saarikivi and K. Heljanko: &lt;em&gt;Using Unfoldings in
Automated Testing of Multithreaded Programs&lt;/em&gt;. In Proceedings of the 27th
IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering (ASE
2012), pages 150-159, 3-7 September 2012, Essen, Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;O. Saarikivi, K. Kähkönen and K. Heljanko: &lt;em&gt;Improving Dynamic Partial
Order Reductions for Concolic Testing&lt;/em&gt;. In Proceedings of the 12th
International Conference on Application of Concurrency to System Design
(ACSD’2012), pages 132-141, 25-29 June 2012, Hamburg, Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;K. Kähkönen, T. Launiainen, O. Saarikivi, J. Kauttio, K. Heljanko, and
I. Niemelä: &lt;em&gt;LCT: An Open Source Concolic Testing Tool for Java
Programs&lt;/em&gt;. In Proceedings of the 6th Workshop on Bytecode Semantics,
Verification, Analysis and Transformation (BYTECODE’2011), pages 75-80,
March 2011, Saarbrücken, Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;Work Experience&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;1 Sept. 2013 – present&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doctoral student&lt;/em&gt;, Aalto University, Department of Computer Science and Engineering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the Education section for details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_8&#34;&gt;1 June 2010 – 31 Aug. 2013&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Research assistant&lt;/em&gt;, Aalto University, Department of Information and Computer Science&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been working on projects researching automated software testing
and verification. I extended the dynamic symbolic execution tool LCT to
support testing multithreaded Java programs. I also implemented a
dynamic partial order reduction algorithm and we published the
improvements I made in the paper “Improving Dynamic Partial Order
Reductions for Concolic Testing”. For my Master’s Thesis I implemented
the Dash algorithm for testing C programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the summer of 2012 I have been employed full time. During previous
teaching periods I have been employed part time, 1 day per week, while
the summers have been full time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_9&#34;&gt;1 June 2009 – 31 Aug. 2009&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Research assistant&lt;/em&gt;, Helsinki University of Technology, Laboratory for Theoretical
Computer Science&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked on a project researching formal methods and automated testing.
I developed a set of utilities to generate test drivers for the
automated testing tool LCT and unit tests from the output of the testing
tool. I also designed and implemented a heuristic for directed testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_10&#34;&gt;Optofidelity Ltd.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17 June 2008 – 29 June 2008&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;36 hours of work on a one-off project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built a sound capture component for a visual programming environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5 June 2007 – 24 Aug. 2007&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Trainee&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main project was a technology demo that used a PTZ camera and a
machine vision library to track a printed target and read a handwritten
phone number from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_11&#34;&gt;Nokia Research Center&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26 June 2006 – 28 July 2006&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Full time trainee&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12 Aug. 2005 – 31 May 2006&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Part time trainee, 12 hours/week&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1 June 2005 – 11 Aug. 2005&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Full time trainee&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1 Sept. 2004 – 31 May 2005&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Part time trainee, 12 hours/week&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work was software development for internal projects. Two of my
projects were concept demos on using image analysis techniques to
generate content in games. One project was a technology demo for a
mobile multiplayer gaming framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This traineeship was part of my education at the Päivölä High School of
Mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_12&#34;&gt;Conferences and Schools&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attended the 25th Nordic Workshop on Programming Theory (NWPT 2013) and
gave a talk titled &lt;em&gt;LCT-D: Test-Guided Proofs for C Programs on LLVM&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attended Summer School Marktoberdorf 2013 (MOD 2013) on software systems
safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attended the 27th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated
Software Engineering (ASE 2012).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attended the 12th International Conference on Application of Concurrency
to System Design (ACSD 2012) to present the paper &lt;em&gt;Improving Dynamic
Partial Order Reductions for Concolic Testing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_13&#34;&gt;Awards and Honours&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was selected to the &lt;strong&gt;Honours Programme in Information and Computer
Science&lt;/strong&gt; at Aalto University for the academic years 2011–2012 and
2012–2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meritorious Winner in the COMAP MCM: Mathematical Contest in
Modeling&lt;/strong&gt; in 2006 with Olli Salli and Matti Nelimarkka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meritorious Winner in the COMAP ICM: Interdisciplinary Contest in
Modeling&lt;/strong&gt; in 2005 with Vihtori Mäntylä and Olli-Petteri Pitkänen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COMAP, the Consortium for Mathematics and Its Applications, is a USA
based organization that holds annual mathematics competitions for
undergraduate level students.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>