<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Frontpage on Olli Saarikivi </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://ulber.iki.fi/collections/frontpage/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Olli Saarikivi</author>
    
    <updated>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 10:49:35 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reitit for Windows Phone 8.1 delayed</title>
      <link>http://ulber.iki.fi/2014/08/reitit-for-windows-phone-8.1-delayed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 10:49:35 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Olli Saarikivi</author>
      <guid>http://ulber.iki.fi/2014/08/reitit-for-windows-phone-8.1-delayed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;float-right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#34;picture&#34; src=&#34;/reitit-80.png&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;drop-cap&#34;&gt;O&lt;/span&gt;ver the summer I have been developing a Windows Phone 8.1 version of my Helsinki metropolitan area route planner app, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.windowsphone.com/fi-fi/store/app/reitit/30e77f37-ef15-4860-b5d2-c4f7ee96f0e4&#34;&gt;Reitit&lt;/a&gt;. The new version is already mostly feature complete. However, the release of the app will be delayed due to problems I have encountered with the new framework:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The app is too slow. Page navigation is noticeably slower than in the old version. One optimization that I employed in the WP7 version was to not use data binding and instead create and update all controls in code-behind. I hoped that this would not be required to get smooth navigation on WP8 class hardware. I will have to do further testing to see what is causing the slow page loading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/xaml/windows.ui.xaml.controls.maps.mapcontrol.aspx&#34;&gt;MapControl&lt;/a&gt; for &amp;ldquo;Windows Phone XAML apps&amp;rdquo; has rendering issues when panning a map that includes UIElement push pins. Basically the push pins don&amp;rsquo;t always move at the same speed as the rest of the map. When dragging a finger on the map, both the map image and the push pins lag behind the touch point, but the map image itself lags &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; resulting in the push pins not staying glued down on to the map.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue with the map control can be tolerated, as the map is otherwise quite a bit more beautiful than the old WP7 map. The page navigation issue, however, is something I will need to fix before publishing the new version.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New homepage</title>
      <link>http://ulber.iki.fi/2014/08/new-homepage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 09:23:49 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Olli Saarikivi</author>
      <guid>http://ulber.iki.fi/2014/08/new-homepage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my new homepage, which I&amp;rsquo;ve set up to have some web presence aside from Facebook. This will be a place to find my up-to-date CV as well as info on any personal projects I may be working on (as soon as I get around to writing about them).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website itself is generated with the static site generator &lt;a href=&#34;http://hugo.spf13.com/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. The theme is a heavily modified version of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hyde&#34;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt; theme. Any comments about the website are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>